[{"question": "Which of the following statements create a dictionary?", "options": ["A. d = {}", "B. d = {\u201cjohn\u201d:40, \u201cpeter\u201d:45}", "C. d = {40:\u201djohn\u201d, 45:\u201dpeter\u201d}", "D. All of the mentioned"], "answer": "D. All of the mentioned"}, {"question": "Suppose d = {\u201cjohn\u201d:40, \u201cpeter\u201d:45}, to delete the entry for \u201cjohn\u201d what command do we use?", "options": ["A.  d.delete(\u201cjohn\u201d:40)", "B.  d.delete(\u201cjohn\u201d)", "C. del d[\u201cjohn\u201d]", "D. del d(\u201cjohn\u201d:40)"], "answer": "C. del d[\u201cjohn\u201d]"}, {"question": "Suppose d = {\u201cjohn\u201d:40, \u201cpeter\u201d:45}. To obtain the number of entries in dictionary which command do we use?", "options": ["A. d.size()", "B. len(d)", "C. size(d)", "D. d.len()"], "answer": "B. len(d)"}, {"question": "Suppose d = {\u201cjohn\u201d:40, \u201cpeter\u201d:45}, what happens when we try to retrieve a value using the expression d[\u201csusan\u201d]?", "options": ["A. Since \u201csusan\u201d is not a value in the set, Python raises a KeyError exception", "B. It is executed fine and no exception is raised, and it returns None", "C. Since \u201csusan\u201d is not a key in the set, Python raises a KeyError exception", "D. Since \u201csusan\u201d is not a key in the set, Python raises a syntax error"], "answer": "C. Since \u201csusan\u201d is not a key in the set, Python raises a KeyError exception"}, {"question": " Which of these about a dictionary is false?", "options": ["A. The values of a dictionary can be accessed using keys", "B. The keys of a dictionary can be accessed using values", "C. Dictionaries aren\u2019t ordered", "D. Dictionaries are mutable"], "answer": "B. The keys of a dictionary can be accessed using values"}, {"question": "hich of the following is not a declaration of the dictionary?", "options": ["A. {1: \u2018A\u2019, 2: \u2018B\u2019}", "B. dict([[1,\u201dA\u201d],[2,\u201dB\u201d]])", "C. {1,\u201dA\u201d,2\u201dB\u201d}", "D. { }"], "answer": "C. {1,\u201dA\u201d,2\u201dB\u201d}"}, {"question": "Which of the following isn\u2019t true about dictionary keys?", "options": ["A.  More than one key isn\u2019t allowed", "B. Keys must be immutable", "C. Keys must be integers", "D. When duplicate keys encountered, the last assignment wins"], "answer": "C. Keys must be integers"}, {"question": "Which of the statements about dictionary values if false?", "options": ["A. More than one key can have the same value", "B. The values of the dictionary can be accessed as dict[key]", "C. Values of a dictionary must be unique", "D. Values of a dictionary can be a mixture of letters and numbers"], "answer": "C. Values of a dictionary must be unique"}, {"question": " If a is a dictionary with some key-value pairs, what does a.popitem() do?", "options": ["A. Removes an arbitrary element", "B. Removes all the key-value pairs", "C. Removes the key-value pair for the key given as an argument", "D. Invalid method for dictionary"], "answer": "A. Removes an arbitrary element"}, {"question": "If b is a dictionary, what does any(b) do?", "options": ["A. Returns True if any key of the dictionary is true", "B. Returns False if dictionary is empty", "C. Returns True if all keys of the dictionary are true", "D. Method any() doesn\u2019t exist for dictionary"], "answer": "A. Returns True if any key of the dictionary is true"}, {"question": "Which one of the following is correct?", "options": ["A. In python, a dictionary can have two same keys with different values.", "B. In python, a dictionary can have two same values with different keys", "C. In python, a dictionary can have two same keys or same values but cannot have two same key-value pai", "D. In python, a dictionary can neither have two same keys nor two same values."], "answer": "B. In python, a dictionary can have two same values with different keys"}, {"question": "Find the output of the following program: Which of these about a dictionary is false?", "options": ["A. The values of a dictionary can be accessed using keys", "B. The keys of a dictionary can be accessed using values", "C. Dictionaries may or may not be ordered", "D. None of the above"], "answer": "B. The keys of a dictionary can be accessed using values"}, {"question": "print(1)", "options": ["A 0", "B 1", "C -1", "D -2"], "answer": "B 1"}]
